Hello! In today's Bug Bounty report explained
you will learn how it was possible to achieve
local remote code execution in playstation now
application due to insecure websocket server.
The vulnerability was reported on hackerone
by Parsia Hakimian and he got $15,000 for it.
Links to the original report and to his twitter
are in the description. Enjoy!
Playstation Now is a cloud gaming subscription service developed
by Sony. It allows streaming games from PS2, PS3 and PS4
on newer consoles and, most importantly for us, on
PCs.
It has a desktop application that users openwhen they want to play a game.
The main application
is called QAS and it's written in C++.
It alsoruns a local WebSocket server on port 1235.
But there is also another application - AGL.
And by default QAS runs it with this URL
argument:
It's written in Electron which uses chromium browser inside. It loads the website from
the URL and presents it to the user.
I've mentionedthat the main application runs the WebSocket
server. Let's now explain what it means.
With HTTP it's always the browser sending a
request and the server can only send responses
And WebSockets were created to allow browsers to
establish asynchronous connection with the server.
It means that both sides can send
messages whenever they want.
However, there are security concerns because HTTP
traffic is protected by Same-Origin-Policy.
It's a mechanism that protects websites from
different domains from stealing each other's data.
But WebSocket connections do not
obey Same-Origin-Policy rules.
And the WebSocket connection is initiated
by the following javascript code:
When it gets executed, such HTTP request is being
sent. And in the Origin header the browser will
put the domain from which this code was executed.
And it's the server's responsibility to verify
if this origin is trusted or not. If it's valid,
the server responds with appropriate response
and the websocket connection is then
established and both sides can communicate.
But the Playstation Now application did not verify
the origin.
So when a user opened the attacker'swebsite while the PS Now application was runningin the background, the attacker could write this
javascript code and it would allow to establish
the connection with the local WebSocket server.
It's because this code would be executed in the
user's browser meaning that the localhost refersto his machine.
But just establishing a websocket
connection does not really have an impact.
Let'ssee what we can do with it. Embedding untrusted
website inside Electron application can be very
harmful but it's not always the case. It depends
on Electron security settings in the application.
If you've watched my video about RCE in Microsoft
Teams, you know how Electron is built and what
nodeIntegration security does. If you didn't I
highly recommend watching it. It's available in
the cart right now, but I will remind those facts
anyway here. So Electron application is composed of
Node main process and the renderer which is
a headless Chromium browser.
And when nodeIntegration is disabled, there is a separation
between the main process and the renderer.
It prohibits the website opened in the renderer
from accessing Node.js API, because it could lead
to remote code execution. Without it the website
opened in the renderer can't just import child_process
and execute code. But the AGL application
used nodeIntegration = true setting which
means that the website opened in the renderer can
do anything using Node.js API and this includes
importing child_process and executing code
which is presented at the moment on the screen.
Let's now put this all together
and see how the full exploit looked.
Normally, messages sent via the WebSocket
connection looked like this:
We have a command, its parameters, the application that calls
the command and the target application.
And one of the commands looked particularly
interesting for us. It was setUrl.
It madethe target application open the provided website
and embed its content to present it to the user.
By default, it was some site from Playstation
server but it was also possible to set this URL
to the exploit you've seen seconds ago.
So the full exploit would look like this:
The attack scenario is that the victim opens this
website while PS Now application is running in
the background. Those first two lines establish a
connection with the local WebSocket server.
Then, we send a WebSocket message with setUrl command
and the parameter is URL that points to our RCEexploit.
As the target application, we choose AGL
because this is the one that runs with Electron.
And when our website is opened, the RCE gets
triggered and the attack is successful.
The vulnerability was fixed and updated versions
of PS Now application are no longer exploitable.
The report was triaged as critical and
was rewarded $15,000 but the researcher
is from Canada, so after taxes he
maybe got half of it to his pocket.
Anyway, if you've learned something new today
leave a like and leave a subscription. Bye!